i guess i mean the thing is there's
there's crazy people in new york city
that's the
they're just there's crazy and there's
crazy people
all over um there's crazy people here
okay
but usually you're in a car and they're
not
think about usually it's like oh they
roll the window up no more crazy you
know
if you're next to a crazy person here
i mean that's your fault you married him
or whatever like that's just you can't
in new york you have no choice i mean
they're on the subway you're just you
ride the subway you're next to every the
subway is a mental institution it is i
mean it takes people places but that is
its secondary purpose it is
i was on the subway one day and this
lady just walked on the subway she
started singing all i want for christmas
is a fish sandwich all i want for
christmas is a fish sandwich
all i want for christmas is a fish
sandwich all i was like come on lady
we're in public here
guess what song has been stuck in my
head for the last two years i can't get
rid of it that woman should not be
homeless she's a hit maker okay she she
may be one of the greatest lyricists of
our time
i've heard 11 taylor swift songs i don't
know the words i know all the words the
fish sandwich and
and guess what nobody's wondering what
to get her for christmas
you know that one woman that rides a
train i want to give her a gift but i
just a dude she wants a fish sandwich
you gotta listen to the lyrics you're
getting caught up in the beat man
[Laughter]
six of you are gonna wake up tomorrow
morning
you're gonna be in the shower
and be like all that why i hate greg
warren i hate him
they sell fruit on the side of the
street in new york
they do they have these uh fruit wagons
uh
i don't know fruit carts fruit wagon
doesn't sound right
fruit wagon sounds like something the
mean kid would say in an 80s movie like
what are you looking at fruit wagon
fruit cards all right these are these
fruit cards and and the thing is they uh
they leave them out at night they don't
they don't put the fruit away they leave
the carts out at night on the street and
there's a guy that sits there all night
long and he watches the fruit
that's his job he's a he's a fruit
watchman
i wonder how you get that i bet you
i bet you it's either an on the way up
thing or an on the way down thing it's
like it's like hey kid you can't just
walk in off the street and become a
night watchman at a bank you got no
experience why don't you go
sit fruit for a couple years and we'll
take a look at you
or or if you two idiots screw this up
one more time you're gonna be staring at
an apple on second avenue for the rest
of your lives now you get out of my
office
you don't need a car in new york you
don't need a car which is you know it's
fine you don't even really miss your car
so you have to walk somewhere to
purchase an item that you used to bring
home in your car
i had to get an ironing board i didn't
think about it i walked like 15 blocks
this hardware store
i was about to get the ironing board i'm
like oh oh no
i'm gonna have to walk home
looking like a surfer who got some bad
directions
and i'm 49 like at my age what do i care
what people think of me i guess i still
do because in my head i was thinking
soon as i walk outside so i'm just going
to be like nice and boring fruit wagon
why don't you arms your little iron
anymore nobody said anything nobody even
looked at me that's the beauty of new
york city if you think you're doing
something weird don't worry about it
there's somebody doing something way way
weirder right next year it was arrogant
to me to think that i was going to get
noticed with just an ironing board
there's professional freaks in that town
there's probably a guy that walks around
with an ironing board and an iron and he
actually irons stuff with no electricity
oh oh that's ironing board reggie give
him a dollar that's what he does
get them wrinkles out dog get them
wrinkles out
the devil doesn't put the wrinkles in
reticle take him out
you get you a fish sandwich for
christmas i heat it up with my iron
[Laughter]
i used to live in a new york city
anybody ever been
that's how i feel about it
i don't want to be too harsh but i'm
very pro climate change because of my
experience in new york city uh i'm very
pro-sea level rising
2 000 a month studio apartment with a
view of a brick wall that smelled like
rotten eggnog
yeah
i'm a little bitter about new york city
and i had to get a job walking dogs
all right because like you know so
expensive and not labs or german short
hairs like
2500 pomeranians that have allergies
stuff like that
i'll get to that in a
second one time in new york city if you
guys have been there's a lot of uh how
should i put i don't want to be
insensitive like psychopaths um
and one day
my car broke down in front of central
park
in the evening
and a new york city crazy man
came up and just said
well what can i do to help
i was like it's no big deal i just have
to jump it and then he said
well if you're gonna jump it you're
gonna need a bike and a ramp
[Laughter]
i was like no i don't think you
understand i don't need that
at all
and i said well there's no way you're
going to jump with your legs you chubby
red-faced pig
it's like all right
fine go get the bike in the ramp
[Laughter]
here's a true story
something i saw in new york city one of
the parks i saw a new york city man
another
crazy person uh
pick up off the ground
some dog poo
[Music]
what was disturbing about it is he did
it just like it belonged to him
oh all right here we go yeah
he's just standing there holding it no
biggie
and i'm watching him
and then he threw it
at a squirrel
and wouldn't you know it provo he got it
and then he just started laughing
hysterically
and i'm watching them like you know i
guess sometimes it really is just about
enjoying the small things
[Laughter]
you guys have been amazing it's almost
time for me to get out of here and it's
so fun
tell you one last joke about new york
before i leave i
got a job walking dogs like i said and
one day
i left the set list to my comedy act
on the counter
of a woman who i walked dogs for
and she had no idea i was a comedian
now a setlist is what comics prepare
before a show we write down our jokes
you know
but she didn't know it was a comic so
she probably just thought it was like a
to-do list or something
so the next day i go in there to get
paid and there's a note attached to my
set list that just says andy i think
this is yours
this is the set list i left on that
lady's counter
wink at man on toilets
[Laughter]
get neighbor to try heroin
buy army uniform at surplus store to
save money at golden corral
cut out roommate's kidney
and at the bottom it says this is all
good stuff
[Laughter]
do this stuff tonight
so i just took my set list
and left a note that said hey don't
worry
i already did that stuff and it was
hilarious
but i took my wife with me to get to get
out of the city to get away from the
city you know i mean like to get like i
we
i live in new york city all right and i
live and i say new york city i live in
manhattan but i live way uptown in
manhattan i live in a section called
washington heights okay which is very
dominican okay and i don't know if you
guys can tell with the lights i'm not
at all
and they pick up on it almost
immediately
i do a magic trick to get out of trouble
in my neighborhood what i mean is
there's not a lot of white people in my
neighborhood so sometimes on the street
i'm the white guy and sometimes that's a
problem okay
so i do this magic trick to get out of
trouble and the trick is i'm a white guy
but i can get whiter
and it's awesome
like i'll do it for you like how is he
going to get wider watch if you saw me
on the street right now like there's a
white guy watch regular white guy
watch this
wider
i know i know
this is how it works okay the magic is
you can change your
all right let's say we're in traffic
we're on broadway and broadway where i
live two lanes but there's always
somebody who wants to make a third lane
and get in front of me no you're not
okay
because you're just gonna stop but i
have to go around you but they're not
gonna let me in no all right when you
don't let somebody in that causes road
rage people get furious right if you're
furious and you look over you don't see
it's me going
then that fury becomes frustration
magic it keeps you from getting shot
okay that's the point
nobody shoots this guy
yeah i i love doing this job i've i've
um been doing comedy everywhere i
started on the east coast i used to live
in new york for a little while that's a
dangerous place anybody ever here ever
live in new york city
yeah a couple people do you live in one
of the five boroughs yeah which one
the bronx give it up for that guy he's
got a knife on him now
he's got a knife
yeah no it's it's i if you love living
one of the five girls in new york city
here's a good survival tip that i
learned when i lived there and it's easy
to remember all you do ready is avoid
okay other people all right
and in times square you're trying to
avoid flyer pamphlet people they are
just trying to put a flyer in your hand
here's what you do there's a technique
for this it's called the full up
technique you carry something in both
hands
now you're full up okay
now you can't accept their flyers or
their pamphlets because you're already
full up i would always carry my cell
phone okay and a handgun and i would be
like
i am full up right now okay
um why don't you give that to this guy
maybe or
one of those two people because i can't
can't pay oh now i'm getting a call
hello
i am on a phone call right now
hold on a second i have to kill somebody
you ever find yourself in the wrong
store i mean just too expensive but you
don't even realize it you know i was
when i was in new york city and i was
just looking at these shirts in this
place and i just see the price tag i go
i go with the shirt they're 900
the shirts a little bit nicer than this
but nine hundred dollars i got the
shirts at nine hundred dollars a guy
goes yeah i go i got i got to get out of
here
he says well we have some less expensive
shirts over there on that wall i said no
i don't think so
i'm pretty sure if these are 900 they're
not 40 bucks over there on that wall
i'm in the wrong place not the wrong
part of this place
i knew it
it doesn't bother me but i come from a
place where women are just beautiful to
the inhabitants
that beautiful spanish island called
bronx new york
yeah
i love it i love being from the bronx
and i love poppies any any latinos in
here no no
well that's all white i mean all right
but i do i mean
you know i'm i'm a poor girl from the
bronx you know and we didn't have much i
drove raggedy cars anytime i've ever
been stuck on the highway with my hood
in the air i know black men saw my hood
up
they kept right on going
but not poppy
poppy will always stop
and ask a stupid question
i'm in the breakdown lane with my hood
in the air
here comes papa mommy what happened
ain't no scotty
i'm sorry that is an absolutely
ridiculous question
who leaves their house to go sit on the
highway with the hood in the air
but i can't even laugh he rebuilt my
transmission right there on the
breakdown
[Applause]
it was incredible he had no toolbox he
had two tools a screwdriver and a magic
marker that's all i saw
when he was finished you know i was
saying thank you and i hit my home but
you gave me a new horn
and they always make you feel so
attractive you know sometimes you feel
down on yourself you don't feel you know
your best all you have to do is just go
to the bronx they're all standing around
you know
and you walk by
and then you hear
i
believe
[Music]
i know what to do
in new york where i'm from is you know a
hodgepodge of everyone and not only
spanish men but west indian men like me
jamaican man isn't that crazy jamaican
man think i'm cute
i'm standing next to this guy we're
talking for like 10 minutes i don't know
him now he wants to be romantic and he
goes
you know why
me really love you
[Music]
i've known you 10 minutes
i did look nice that day so i'm like why
true story i couldn't make this up if i
tried he goes girl we love you so much
because
how you're just so fat
and black
like me mother
you say i'm fat and black
like your mother
all right well you know
i'll sleep with you this time
next time you need to come up with a
better line
[Music]
fat and black
this is why i'm single by the way isn't
it
[Music]
this is my first time here in provo and
you i have to say you people could not
have been any more friendly and polite
and as a new yorker it's really freaking
me out
you have no idea how terrifying it is to
see a stranger approach you when you're
a new yorker who is smiling
we don't know what to do it's like
seeing a raccoon during the daytime you
think
who should i call to prevent this from
happening it's
i don't know i i apologize i've just
been pepper spraying everyone out of
habit just
set some boundaries
so it is nice to see you guys uh i do
come to you from new york now i just
want to check round of applause who's
been to new york city
[Applause]
i thought you looked familiar
new york it's in an amazing place you
know i'll tell you sometimes i'm on that
subway platform i start thinking
maybe i should pee too
it doesn't smell like anyone else is
holding it in here
[Laughter]
i see things i can't even comprehend
anymore i was waiting for my train the
other day i'm standing on the subway
platform i'm looking at the tracks and
watching the rats run around
which is uh it's fun it's like being on
safari
you'll even pick favorites oh look at
brownie he's got a chicken wing good for
you brownie
[Laughter]
and don't feel bad for new york city
rats they're doing fine
i've never seen a thin rat
oh they're fat they're moving slow
they're like little sweet potatoes
dragging around in front of you
but i saw this rat run by and he was
missing half his tail ah
i don't need that
i don't need a rat with a backstory
where i have to think ooh i wonder what
he's been through
but i never i've never seen that before
so i turned to the guy next to me and i
said did you see that rat
he's missing half his tail
and the guy said
was it the last half
yeah of course it was the last half it
you can't have rat
no tail
then tail again it doesn't make any
sense
no one's ever missing the middle part
once it's gone it's gone you don't see a
guy with no arm and a hand hanging out
in the side
i went to new york recently and i tried
to hail a taxi and i caught a pigeon
uh
[Applause]
all right
[Music]
[Applause]
just let me know when you're ready man
i still don't think he's ready
i don't want to hurt nobody
[Music]
i didn't even know i had the pigeon till
i was in the camp
it didn't make it
[Music]
oh no
tell me about the rabbits
one christmas we went to new york city
to watch them skate in that uh
rockefeller center that was interesting
you should do it it's really fun
new york city is kind of a tough place
don't get lost
if you get lost in new york city just
buy an apartment and live on that street
for the rest of your life
not me i go up to the guy i go hey you
tell me how to find rockefeller center
that guy goes hey yo sure thing no
problem
go down this street right here it ain't
tree lights make a left two blocks make
a right right there on the corner you
see a store go in there and buy a map
[Laughter]
thank you officer
i'm a region from new york city
i get this all the time you don't sound
like a real black new yorker
i think all black new york could sell
like this here say what up with that
what's your man what's going on yo yo
what's up what's up
i got family that talks like that as
soon as i don't open the door in new
york it's kind yeah boy you're weird
come here yo give us a kiss step ahead
step in give us a kiss like yeah settle
down grandma just